

I'm a writer, whether it's poetry or code, that loves taking a blank screen and bringing it to life. Because of my writing and teaching experience, I can explain complex ideas simply and spot errors quickly. I build apps with clean, readable code—and lots of coffee.

## **Contact**

714.345.9517 hello@tiffanymonroe.com tiffanymonroe.com

LinkedIn • GitHub atiffanymonroe

# Skills

HTML • CSS • JavaScript jQuery • Angular • Node.js • React

Express • MongoDB

Heroku · Git · GitHub

Ruby • Rails • Rspec • Postgres

MVC · RESTful Routes

Slack · Zoom

### Disneyland Decoded

September 2017

A fully responsive travel planning app created in a two-week sprint.

Developer Experience

Tech: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Angular.js, Ruby, Rails, JWT

#### **Travel Books**

September 2017

A private, online journal for travelers who love to read. Created in a five-day sprint.

Tech: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Angular.js, Ruby, Rails, JWT

#### **Dad Joke Factory**

August 2017

Random dad joke generator that consumes a third-party API.. Created as a week-long sprint.

Tech: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, MEAN Stack

#### **Creative Blogging**

August 2017

A student-friendly classroom app. Created as a week-long sprint. **Tech: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Node.js, MongoDB, Express, EJS** 

# Education

Web Development
Immersive

General Assembly 2017

#### **Creative Writing, MFA**

Chapman University 2013

#### English, MA

Chapman University 2010

#### English, BA

Chapman University 2007

# Other Experience

#### **Writing Instructor**

Chapman U, CSULB, Cypress College | 2013-2016 Developed courses in writing & rhetoric.

#### **Website Administrator**

Remote | 2011-2015

Personalized a Wordpress site using a customizable theme, site integration, and FTP. Created a interactive, digital poetry project of over 100 poems for graduate course.

#### Writer / Editor / Tutor

Cypress College, Chapman University | 2008-2010 Tutored students to plan, prioritize, and complete complex writing assignments. Worked on a 3-person team to develop a Tutoring Manual for a team of 20+ tutors.